Ryan Devenney

Phone: 980-228-6523 | Matthews, NC | Email: rwdevenney@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryandevenney67/ | GitHub: https://github.com/ryand67 |

Portfolio: http://ryandevenneycom/

Summary

Creative and artistic Full Stack Web Developer with a background in freelance Audio Engineering and Sound Design. Adept at producing professional final products using dedication, attention to detail and a willingness to learn to each project.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Next.js, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, VS Code, MySQL Workbench, Robo 3T, Heroku

Completed Projects

TravelSalesGroup | https://github.com/ryand67/TSG-Site | http://www.travelsalesgroup.com

- Responsible for creative content, design and development of travel agency website.
- React, CSS, Node.is

Squawkr | https://github.com/ryand67/Squawkr | https://squawkr-uncc.herokuapp.com/

- Designed message board/social media platform enabling users to share ideas with others.
- Responsibilities: Front end design and backend/database implementation.
- HTML, CSS, JS/jQuery, Nodejs, MySQL

Innovation Auto Repair

https://github.com/JRivera-31/Innovation-Auto-Repair | https://innovation-auto-repair.vercel.app/

- Auto repair company App designed to modernize customer experience. Allows users to book and manage appointments and receive status updates through App versus calls to shop.
- Responsibilities: Database functionality, calendar functionality, and front-end assistance.
- Next.js, CSS, MongoDB, Node.js

Weather Dashboard

https://github.com/ryand67/Weather-Dashboard | https://ryand67.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- An app that allows users to check the current weather of any city and receive a 5-day forecast.
- Responsibilities: Front end aesthetics and app functionality.
- HTML, CSS, JS/jQuery

Experience

Freelance Audio/Visual/Musician Technician, Charlotte, NC

2015-2020

Contracted by bands, venues, and organizations to perform audio and visual tech support.

Music and Media Production Director, 801 South/Matthews UMC, Matthews, NC

2015 - 2018

- Led 12 volunteers charged with producing and performing musical portion of church service.
- Responsible for creation of audio/video presentation designed to complement service.

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: UNCC, Charlotte, NC

2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Some College: UNCC, Charlotte, NC

2015-2019

75 credits of a bachelor of science in computer science.

High School Diploma: David W. Butler High School, Matthews, NC

2015